ADAM WATTERS

adamwatters.nyc • adamwatters11@gmail.com • 412.713.1344 • NYC, New York

SUMMARY

Visually inclined engineer with full-stack experience. Builder of clean, uncluttered, and sometimes beautiful UIs. Believer in declarative and functional JavaScript. Opinionated about SCSS conventions. Vigilant writer of unit and integration tests. Work-flow automator and optimizer. Motivated by data; wants to know how new code affects clicks, signups, etc. People person who helps teammates be the best they can be.

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML5	React	D3	Git	CasperJS
CSS/SCSS	Backbone	Ruby-on-Rails	Grunt	PhantomCSS
JavaScript	jQuery	Node	Webpack	Mixpanel

WORK EXPERIENCE

Contract Engineer, Health-Kick.com

Jan 2016 - March 2016

- planned and built responsive UI for browsing health and fitness deals
- migrated site from a drag-and-drop solution to a Ruby-on-Rails application

Front End Web Engineer, TheLadders.com

Dec 2014 - Nov 2015

- increased sign-ups by building SEO optimized, content rich public pages
- implemented salary data visualizations for the guest job seeker experience
- · prototyped and created a resume review tool

PROJECTS

Library Catalogue, Heartwood School For Homebuilding Crafts

- worked with users to determine application requirements
- designed and built catalogue for small library using Ruby-on-Rails

InstructaBubbles

- built a Node back-end for retrieving and storing JSON data from the Instructables API
- used D3.js to generate bubble elements sized and positioned by number of views

EDUCATION

The Recurse Center, "a self-directed learning retreat for programmers" Sept - Nov 2014

- pair programmed and collaborated with talented programmers from around the world
- presented on the technical details of web development projects
- built web browser versions of classic arcade and board games
- implemented algorithms and data structures

Bucknell University, B.A. in Economics

Sept 2007- May 2011